They took the American dream for a ride
Ford v Ferrari is a drama, action, history film directed by James Mangold.
American car designer Carroll Shelby and the British-born driver Ken Miles work together to battle corporate interference, the laws of physics, and their own personal demons
to build a revolutionary race car for Ford Motor Company and take on the dominating race cars of Enzo Ferrari at the 24 Hours of Le Mans in France in 1966.
Carroll Shelby, played by Matt Damon.
Ken Miles, played by Christian Bale.
Lee Iacocca, played by Jon Bernthal.
Mollie Miles, played by Caitríona Balfe.
Leo Beebe, played by Josh Lucas.
Peter Miles, played by Noah Jupe.
Ford v Ferrari (titled Le Mans '66 in some European countries) is a 2019 American biographical sports drama film
directed by James Mangold and written by Jez Butterworth, John-Henry Butterworth, and Jason Keller.
It stars Matt Damon and Christian Bale, with Jon Bernthal, Caitríona Balfe, Tracy Letts,
Josh Lucas, Noah Jupe, Remo Girone, and Ray McKinnon in supporting roles.
The plot follows a determined team of American and English engineers and designers, led by automotive designer Carroll Shelby and his English driver, Ken Miles, who are hired by
Henry Ford II and Lee Iacocca to build a race car to defeat the perennially dominant Italian racing team Scuderia Ferrari at the 1966 24 Hours of Le Mans race in France.
Ford v Ferrari had its world premiere at the Telluride Film Festival on August 30, 2019, and was theatrically released in the United States on November 15, 2019, by 20th Century Fox to critical and commercial success; critics praised
the performances (particularly Bale and Damon), Mangold's direction, the editing, the sound design and the racing sequences, and it was chosen by the National Board of Review as one of the ten best films of the year.
At the 92nd Academy Awards, the film received four nominations, including
Best Picture, and won Best Film Editing and Best Sound Editing.
Bale also received nominations for the Golden Globe Award for Best Actor – Drama and the Screen
Actors Guild Award for Outstanding Performance by a Male Actor in a Leading Role.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, car
race, sports, car mechanic, biography.
The tone is emotional.